[{"question":"Fluorescent lamp can be operated on -","answers":{"a":"AC supply","b":"DC supply","c":"Both AC & DC supply","d":"Satisfactory only on supply"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"A capacitor is connected across the fluorescent lamp circuit in order to -","answers":{"a":"Eliminate the noise","b":"Limit the current","c":"Improve the power factor of lamp","d":"All of these"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"The flicker effect of fluorescent lamp is more pronounced as -","answers":{"a":"Lower voltages","b":"Higher voltages","c":"Higher frequencies","d":"Lower frequencies"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"Power factor of incandescent lamp -","answers":{"a":"0.8 leading","b":"0.8 lagging","c":"Unity","d":"Zero"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Power factor angle of a purely inductive load -","answers":{"a":"0°","b":"90°","c":"-90°","d":"120°"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"Disadvantages of low power factor -","answers":{"a":"Large kW rating","b":"High kVAR rating","c":"Large kVA rating","d":"Any of the above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"A power factor capacitor designed for 10kVAR at 415V was found to be operating at 400V. the effective of the capacitor would be -","answers":{"a":"9.6kVAR","b":"10kVAR","c":"10.8kVAR","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"The nearest kVAR compensation required for improving the power factor of a 100kW load from 0.8 lag to unity power factor is -","answers":{"a":"50kVAr","b":"75KVAr","c":"100kVAr","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"It voltage is reduced from 230V to 190V for a fluorescent lamp , it will result in -","answers":{"a":"Increased in power consumption","b":"Decrease in power consumption","c":"Increased light levels","d":"No change in power consumption"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"Power is the ratio of( P= active power, Q=reactive power, S =apparent power) -","answers":{"a":"cosΦ=P/S","b":"cosΦ=Q/S","c":"cosΦ=P/Q","d":"cosΦ=Q/P"},"correctAnswer":"a"}]

